# Chuanbin Liu

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

My research interests span Medical Image Analysis, Fine-grained Image Analysis and Weakly-supervised Learning. The noteworthy research project of mine is applying Deep Learning into Pediatric Orthopaedics. I am skilled at python and matlab coding, and experienced of Linux server management. I am an enthusiastic and progressive man, and a reliable team leader.

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Phone: +86-13155167692

Email: lcb592@mail.ustc.edu.cn

Homepage: home.ustc.edu.cn/~lcb592

GitHub: https://github.com/liuboss1992

#### **EDUCATION**

09/2015-Present Doctor of Information and Communication Engineering

University of Science and Technology of China (USTC)

09/2011-06/2015 Bachelor of Applied Physics

University of Science and Technology of China (USTC)

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

## 09/2018-Present Deep Learning for Fine-grained Image Analysis

Independent Completor

 Propose a novel bidirectional attention-recognition model to actualize a bidirectional reinforcement of attention and recognition learning for weakly-supervised Fine-grained Object Classification.

One Journal paper submitted to IEEE TMM.

One patent accepted by CNIPA.

## 05/2018-Present Deep Learning for Diagnosing Developmental Dysplasia of the Hip

Project Leader

• To resolve the temporal diversity and pathological deformity challenge in X-ray based diagnosis of DDH, convert the detection of a landmark to the **detection/segmentation** of the landmark's local neighborhood patch. **Spatial attention** and **Adversarial learning** are also employed to deal with the false positive detection.

One conference paper accepted by MICCAI 2019.

One patent accepted by CNIPA.

Research in use by Anhui Provincial Children's Hospital.

### 09/2017-Present Deep Learning for Pediatric Bone Age Assessment

Independent Completor

Propose a novel weakly-supervised learning approach for Bone Age Assessment, which can
discover and extract the discriminative bone parts without human prior. State-of-art
performance has been achieved, and the proposed method exhibits interpretability,
consistency and inspiration with human prior knowledge.

One conference paper accepted by MICCAI 2019.

One patent accepted by CNIPA.

Research in use by Anhui Provincial Children's Hospital.

## 09/2015-09/2017 Multimedia Network Design based on Game Theory

Project Participant

Consider the network applications as game players driven by their best self-interest. A novel
Media-attribute Switching is proposed with the idea of Mechanism Design. It can provide
incentives for applications to label their media-attributes honestly, thus to protect the
multimedia network with order and efficiency. Scalable Video Coding and MobilityFirst
Network are also involved in this research.

One conference paper submitted to MMM2020.

## 07/2013-09/2014 Equipment Development for Particle Detection

Independent Completor

Design a front-head software for detecting magnetic flux of nuclear fusion.

Equipment in use by Southwestern Institute of Physics.

• Design an **analog circuit preamplifier** for detecting neutron flux of **nuclear fission**.

Equipment in use by Shanghai Institute of Applied Physics.

### **VOLUNTEER & ASSISTANT EXPERIENCES**

## 09/2014-07/2017 Teaching Assistant of Design Innovation

Teaching Assistant in USTC Design Innovation Course as well as Stanford University Global
 Alliance for Redesign. Master the skill of project management, team collaboration and
 leadership.

## 09/2012-01/2015 Volunteer Assistant of Psychotherapists

 Assist the psychotherapist to help the student with psychological problem. Master the skill of listening, observing and psychological counseling.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Chuanbin Liu, Hongtao Xie, et al. Extract Bone Parts without Human Prior: End-to-end Convolutional Neural Network for Pediatric Bone Age Assessment. MICCAI 2019
- Chuanbin Liu, Hongtao Xie, et al. Misshapen Pelvis Landmark Detection by Spatial Local Correlation Mining for Diagnosing Developmental Dysplasia of the Hip. MICCAI 2019
- Fanchao Lin, Chuanbin Liu, et al. Semantic-embedding and Shape-aware U-net for Ultrasound Eyeball Segmentation. ICME 2019.
- Zhihua Shang, Chuanbin Liu, et al. Potential of Attention Mechanism for Classification of Optical Coherence Tomography Images. VCIP 2019.
- Chuanbin Liu, Hongtao Xie, et al. Bidirectional Attention-Recognition Model for Fine-grained Object Classification. IEEE Transactions on Multimedia. (under review)
- Chuanbin Liu, Hongtao Xie, et al. Law is Order: Protecting Multimedia Network Transmission by Game Theory and Mechanism Design. MMM 2020. (under review)

#### **HONORS & AWARDS**

07/2017	CVPR 2019 Contest on Mitosis Detection in Phase Contrast Microscopy Image Sequences (3 <sup>rd</sup> )
09/2016	Excellent Teaching Assistant Award
03/2014	China Undergraduate Physics Tournament Award (Grade 2)
12/2013	Chung-Yao Chao Talent Students Scholarship